$\begin{array}{l} \mbox{joji_antony@gmx.com} \\ +91\ 96323\ 41954 \end{array}$

Profile

Back end leaning full stack software engineer with 6+ years of professional experience building IT infrastructure software. Proficient in developing software systems that have very high requirements of stability, security and scale. Deeply committed to usability, maintainability and security. Loves shipping, helping businesses and customers succeed.

Education

Undergraduate College Education

College of Engineering, Trivandrum

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering

Technical Skills

Languages and Frameworks

Go, Python, C, C++, Java (EE, Hibernate), Javascript (React, Redux), Perl

Tools

Docker, Postgres, MySQL, Jboss, Git, Maven, Linux Containers etc

Platforms

Nutanix Enterprise Cloud, Amazon Web Services, UNIX, Windows

Work Experience and Projects

Work Experience Employed at Arista Networks since April 2018

Arista CloudVision Portal

2018 - Present

Currently working on bringing next generation network management to enterprises

Nutanix Xtract 2016 - 2018

Roles and Responsibilities

- Design, implement, support and lead new feature development for Nutanix Xtract
- Enable QA engineers, documentation team and front end developers
- Support customers through on-call support

Accomplishments

- Lead the AHV hypervisor support feature in Nutanix Xtract for DBs
- Implemented error handling and remediation of Nutanix Xplorer
- Lead the release of AMF Xplorer 1.0

HPE Hyperconverged cloud

2016 - 2016

Front end developer at HPE Hyper converged cloud team

Roles and Responsibilities

- Implement the User Experience designed by designers for HPE HCI
- Iterate on designs and provide critical design feedback for designers
- Deliver a usable and useful hyper converged product on time

Accomplishments

Implemented Image Management

Technologies

ReactJS, Webpack, Gulp, SASS

HP Network Management Center

2013 - 2016

Worked as a core developer and security engineer for HP's Network Management Software called Network Node Manager i

Also worked as lead developer and lab support engineer for NNMi Network Engineer's Toolset

Roles and Responsibilities

- Design and implement new features end to end from front end to back end
- Enable other team members like QA, test automation, documentation members
- Mentor new team members
- Take lead and innovate to improve process and communicate the value delivered

Accomplishments

- Improving SNMP v3 USM specification compliance in the SNMP stack
- Enabling Network Function Virtualization support
- Port the Network Engineer's Tool set to Linux
- Add support for Safari on Mac
- Adding CSRF protection to the NNMi
- Released NNMi SPI NET 10.0, 10.10, 10.20, NNMi 10.10 and NNMi 10.20

Technologies

Java EE, JavaScript Dojo framework, Java Swing, etc

HP Network Node Manager 7.x lab support

2011 - 2013

Lab support engineer for Hewlett-Packard's premier Network Management Solution called NNM $\,$

Roles and Responsibilities

- Triage and solve customer reported issues through analyzing core dumps and logs
- Deliver timely hot fixes and release patches

Accomplishments

- Solved many multi-threading issues (ACE framework)
- Solved many cache coherence issues
- Released NNM 7.53 Intermediate Patches 31 and 32

Technologies

C, C++, Perl, SQL, Java

Side projects

Plivo Call Center

2015-Present

Functional call center application using Plivo API running on the Heroku Platform https://github.com/simula67/plivo-callcenter

Open source

Perl 6 LWP

Merged a patch to Perl 6 LWP to match output of Perl 5 LWP https://github.com/simula67/perl6-lwp-simple

Perl 6 Test Suite

Merged a patch to re factor some of Perl 6 official test suite https://github.com/simula67/roast

Online Profiles

Blog: https://simula67.wordpress.com about.me: https://about.me/jojiantony